<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
  <title>Jonathan Sacerdoti at The Spectator</title>
  <link>https://www.spectator.co.uk/writer/jonathan-sacerdoti/</link>
  <description>Latest articles by Jonathan Sacerdoti from The Spectator</description>
  <item>
  <title>Saudi Arabia and the UAE’s proxy war in Yemen</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/saudi-arabia-and-the-uaes-proxy-war-in-yemen/</link>
  <description>The escalation that emerged overnight in southern Yemen did not originate on the battlefield but in a relatively quiet logistical operation. It began with the arrival of two ships carrying weapons and military vehicles from the United Arab Emirates, docking at the port of Mukalla in Hadramawt. The cargo was unloaded without coordination with the</description>
  <pubDate>30 December 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>We need to talk about Islam</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/we-need-to-talk-about-islam/</link>
  <description>I did not come to Islam through theology. I came to it through fear, threat and hatred directed at me and the world I live in. I think the first time I became aware of something called Islam was in 1989, when Salman Rushdie was sentenced to death by Iran’s ‘Supreme Leader’ for writing his</description>
  <pubDate>29 December 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Why is Alaa Abd el-Fattah's return a 'top priority' for Keir Starmer?</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/why-is-alaa-abd-el-fattahs-return-a-top-priority-for-keir-starmer/</link>
  <description>Apparently it has been a “top priority” for Keir Starmer and his government, since the moment they came to office, to return Alaa Abd el-Fattah to the United Kingdom. A man granted British citizenship only in December 2021. A man who had previously described Britons as “british dogs and monkeys”, who wrote that he “rejoice[s]</description>
  <pubDate>27 December 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Iran has a ceaseless obsession with Israel</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/irans-obsession-with-israel-is-ceaseless/</link>
  <description>When Benjamin Netanyahu arrives in Florida at Donald Trump’s Mar-a-Lago estate in a few days’ time, near the top of his agenda will be a sober accounting of Iranian military activity and what it may yet presage. He will brief the President on a sustained sequence of Iranian ballistic-missile drills conducted across multiple regions, the</description>
  <pubDate>23 December 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The crackdown on 'globalise the intifada' chants is too little, too late</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/the-police-crackdown-on-globalise-the-intifada-chants-is-too-little-too-late/</link>
  <description>Protesters chanting ‘globalise the intifada’ will now be arrested, according to the heads of Greater Manchester Police and the Metropolitan Police. The announcement has been framed as a response to a ‘changed context’. But what it actually represents is an admission, belated and heavy, that the authorities spent years refusing to see what was directly</description>
  <pubDate>18 December 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Why won’t the West defend Jews?</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/why-cant-the-west-defend-jews/</link>
  <description>Bondi Beach is not occupied territory. Yet a Jewish celebration there ended in blood. It is not within a military zone, not contested land, not an ‘open air prison’, but still, among civilians, on a day marked for celebration, Jews were once again slaughtered, picked off by a Muslim father and son who were motivated</description>
  <pubDate>15 December 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>For Jews, the Bondi beach shooting is grimly recognisable</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/the-horror-of-the-bondi-beach-shooting/</link>
  <description>The attack at Bondi beach during a Hanukkah celebration, killing nine, has sent a fresh wave of horror through the Jewish diaspora. What might once have been regarded as unthinkable – a targeted assault on a Jewish gathering in the heart of a peaceful, democratic society – has now become grimly recognisable. It must be</description>
  <pubDate>14 December 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Piers Morgan fell into Nick Fuentes’s trap</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/piers-morgan-fell-into-nick-fuentess-trap/</link>
  <description>When Michael Gove introduced me to Piers Morgan last week at the Spectator Christmas reception, Morgan seized my hand and beamed, ‘I know Jonathan. We’re old friends.’ This was generous of him, not least because it isn’t true. We’d met once before, briefly. But some months earlier I had written a critique of his YouTube show</description>
  <pubDate>9 December 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The BBC's anti-Semitism training is an offensive parody</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/the-bbcs-antisemitism-training-is-an-offensive-parody/</link>
  <description>The BBC has unveiled its compulsory training course for all staff on how not to be racist to Jews. I completed the online module and found it laughable, feeble and entirely beside the point. This isn’t education. It’s parody. A cartoonish exercise in HR-driven pseudo-virtue, dressed up as moral instruction. I have written before that</description>
  <pubDate>8 December 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Marwan Barghouti isn't the 'Palestinian Mandela'</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/marwan-barghouti-isnt-the-palestinian-mandela/</link>
  <description>Some scoffed when Donald Trump thought to tap Tony Blair’s decades of involvement in the Middle East for his future plans in Gaza. Perhaps they were right to. But not to worry: the global search for strategic wisdom has now been resolved. The path to peace lies not through seasoned statesmen or regional experts, but</description>
  <pubDate>4 December 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Nigel Farage must come clean about his Dulwich College schooldays</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/nigel-farage-must-come-clean-about-his-dulwich-college-schooldays/</link>
  <description>The allegations concerning Nigel Farage’s conduct as a schoolboy have returned with unusual force, not because the country is suddenly preoccupied with the internal sociology of Dulwich College, but because Farage now leads a party that sits at the centre of the national debate. Any claim about his past, however old and recycled, is inevitably</description>
  <pubDate>28 November 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The revelations about what the Gaza hostages suffered are the most painful yet</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/its-time-to-listen-to-the-stories-of-the-gaza-hostages/</link>
  <description>The Israeli hostages recently freed from Gaza have begun to speak, and among the new revelations is that some were subjected to sexual assault and degradation, including male hostages. They describe being stripped, groped, violated, and threatened at gunpoint. The scale and cruelty of what they endured should have triggered sustained, front-page attention in the</description>
  <pubDate>27 November 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A lethal standoff is playing out deep beneath Gaza</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/a-lethal-standoff-is-playing-out-deep-beneath-gaza/</link>
  <description>In 1929, René Magritte painted a picture that has since become iconic in both art and philosophy. The Treachery of Images depicts a finely detailed tobacco pipe with a caption beneath: Ceci n’est pas une pipe – ‘This is not a pipe’. Magritte’s point is subtle and enduring. It is indeed not a pipe, but an</description>
  <pubDate>24 November 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>What Trump's Gaza peace plan means for Israel</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/what-trumps-gaza-peace-plan-means-for-israel/</link>
  <description>This may not be the conclusion Israel imagined when it launched its campaign in Gaza. Not all the hostage bodies are home. Hamas is bruised, but not broken. The region remains volatile. Yet even as combat continues, the United Nations Security Council, backed by an American administration long assumed to be ‘pro-Israel’, yesterday endorsed a</description>
  <pubDate>18 November 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The rot at the BBC runs far deeper than Tim Davie</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/the-rot-at-the-bbc-runs-far-deeper-than-tim-davie/</link>
  <description>The resignations at the top of the BBC mark a critical juncture for an institution long seen as a pillar of British public life. Yet their departures, while welcome, are insufficient. The BBC’s failure is not confined to the mistakes of individual executives. It is institutional, entrenched, and long overdue for a reckoning. The BBC</description>
  <pubDate>10 November 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The looming threat to Israel</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/the-looming-threat-to-israel/</link>
  <description>In the aftermath of war, a new front opens. Not in the ruins of Gaza’s cities, but in the corridors of diplomacy, where maps are redrawn with words and allegiances. Israel now finds itself encircled not by tanks but by treaties, resolutions, and incentives: a web of international manoeuvres that promises ‘stability’ while redefining the</description>
  <pubDate>7 November 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hamas's return is revealing Gaza's true colours</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/hamass-return-is-revealing-gazas-true-colours/</link>
  <description>Remember that weird little Covid ritual of 2020, when every Thursday at 8pm people stepped out onto their doorsteps and applauded? Banging saucepans, clapping their hands, they lit up the miserable skies with cheers for the National Health Service. It was mawkish, and orchestrated to the point of theatre. But its aim was to express</description>
  <pubDate>31 October 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hamas is testing Israel's patience</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/hamas-is-testing-israels-patience/</link>
  <description>In the wake of yet another rupture in the fragile ceasefire between Israel and Hamas, the region finds itself suspended in an unstable equilibrium – tense, volatile, but for now, deliberately held back from tipping into open war. On Tuesday, Hamas terrorists launched a coordinated double attack against Israeli troops operating inside the designated ‘yellow</description>
  <pubDate>29 October 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Hamas's hostage remains deception is a new low</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/hamass-hostage-remains-deception-is-a-new-low/</link>
  <description>The grotesque return of a body part falsely presented as one of Israel’s remaining hostages marks a new low in Hamas’s campaign of calculated cruelty. Israeli authorities confirmed today that the casket transferred by Hamas did not contain the remains of any of the 13 captives whose remains are still known to be in Gaza.</description>
  <pubDate>28 October 2025</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Palestinian question can no longer be ignored</title>
  <link>https://spectator.com/article/dividing-gaza-in-two-presents-a-fresh-test-for-israel/</link>
  <description>The war in Gaza has not ended; it has changed its shape. What began as a brutal confrontation has now hardened into a political and geographic experiment, one whose contours may define the region’s next decade. Beneath the surface of ceasefires and reconstruction plans lies a deeper transformation: the reappearance of the Palestinian question, after</description>
  <pubDate>27 October 2025</pubDate>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
